Alexandru Bondor

React Developer - UI/UX Designer

+40751267236 | alexandru.bondor@gmail.com | Bucharest, Romania, open for remote

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a React Developer - UI/UX Designer with 5+ years' experience developing Web-Apps and software solutions for businesses of different sizes. I have a vast knowledge in the IT field and the film industry. Involving myself in multiple projects in both fields, with the experience that I gathered, I started two companies that benefit from both my technical and artistic side. Moreover, sharing this knowledge with people that requested my help, I managed to guide them to their desired results. Continuously desiring to evolve, I am always searching for new opportunities.

TECH STACK

Front End	React, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
Back End	JavaScript, C#, C++, Electron
Databases	MySQL, MongoDB, ElectronDB
Robotics	Arduino, Texas Instruments Microcontroller
Content Management Systems	Wix, Shopify, Wordpress
Design	Adobe Photoshop, Lightroom, XD

EXPERIENCE

Consultant - React / Fullstack Developer | Heyday | Bucharest, Romania

2022 - Present

Heyday is a tech company that works with international clients by offering software solutions such as web-apps, websites, along with all the media content that they might need.

- My work involves discussing with clients and finding out what they need in order to grow their business on the software side. I
 am building new web-applications or adding features to already existing systems, using React.
- This role requires me to recognize the client's needs and recommend features to improve their web-applications.
- I am in direct communication with Project Managers and I give daily updates on my work during our meetings.
- Technologies: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, C#, Adobe XD, Git
- Responsibilities: Building scalable and user-friendly platforms, while keeping the clients constantly updated regarding the work that is being done on their project.

InVibes is a tech company that creates premium in-feed advertisements, reaching high numbers of people in a constantly growing list of countries.

- My main focus is building new products that we release every month
- The workflow starts from creating wireframes for the product idea, presenting it to clients and then building a working design with all its functionalities
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Lightroom, Adobe XD, Git
- Responsibilities: Creating products through a marketing perspective thinking of user interfaces and interactions that will bring awareness to our clients' brand. Writing scalable and easy to use code, making templates that do not require much time to understand and modify for future use.

Co-founder | WebReach | Bucharest, Romania

2020 - Present

WebReach is a consulting and software company that offers all the services that a business needs to have in order to achieve a strong online presence.

- Since the start of the company, we worked with international clients, building or consolidating their brands
- My role was to design product websites that would generate as many sales as possible
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Node, React, Angular, MongoDB, Electron, Wix, Shopify, Wordpress, Git
- Responsibilities: Approaching possible clients and suggesting ways in which they could improve their business from a marketing standpoint (Web Design, Commercials, Digital Content, SEO). Creating new designs or content for their web-pages and social media is the main focus of my work.

Co-founder | Astraeus Production | London, United Kingdom

2020 - Present

Astraeus Production is a British company specialised in audio and video production and post-production.

- I built the architecture for the company's and clients' websites and web-apps
- <u>Technologies</u>: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Git
- Responsibilities: Working together with a team of videographers, sound engineers, directors or actors, in order to create feature films, series, commercials, music videos or film scores. Sound Design / Video Editing / Photography

Head of Web Development | Aube Production | London, United Kingdom

2017 - 2020

Aube Production is a production house based in London, Paris and Vietnam. We are doing sound-design, location recording, commercials, audiobooks, video games and more multi-media related services.

- I built the architecture for the company's and clients' websites and web-apps
- I maintained and updated their platforms

- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Git
- Responsibilities: Creating web content for the company and their partners (websites, promotional content, music)

Frontend Developer | Nuffield Health | London, United Kingdom

2017 - 2018

I have built and designed the Front-End of a health data visualisation web-app used by clients of Nuffield Health

- I built the the front-end and design of a health data visualisation platform used by the Nuffield Health's clients
- I maintained and updated their platform
- Technologies: Vue.JS, Azure, React, Node, Victory, FHiR, Apache Drill, CSS, Git
- Responsibilities: Creating wireframes for the platform and transforming the client's preferred ones into working code.

OTHER EXPERIENCES

Software Developer ROT Systems Romania	
• Responsibilities: Working on the design of a cross-platform transportation app.	
Software Engineering Intern NXP Semiconductors Romania	2017- 2017
Responsibilities: Building self-driving car software	
IoT Developer FlySim Romania	2016 - 2017
• Responsibilities: Building IOT solutions, from solar trackers, to voice activated vehicle security systems	
Junior Developer Microsoft Romania	
• Responsibilities: Building apps for the newly released Windows 8.1	

EDUCATION

Master's Degree UCL London, United Kingdom	2016 – 2020
Computer Science, A Colegiul National Tudor Vianu Bucharest, Romania	2012 - 2016
A* Oxford Royale Academy Oxford, United Kingdom	2014 – 2014

ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES

Software Engineer for COVID-19 breathing devices (Volunteer) Romanian Health Ministry	2020 – 2020
Teaching C/C++ to students, starting from secondary school, until the first two years of University	2015 - 2021
Teaching Web Design / Photography / Photoshop	2018 - 2021

PROFILES

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexandru-bondor/				
Astraeus Production: http://astraeusproduction.com/	-	alexander@astraeusproduction.com		
WehReach: https://wehreach.ro/	_	alexandru@webreach.ro		